when working with documents there may be
some information now you wish to display
consistently throughout the documents so
if you had 20 pages you may want to have
the date and the company logo on every
page and also a page numbers to do that
you would use the headers and footers
section of the document now the headers
and footers aren't displayed by default
you have to actually access them to
enter the information so to do that as
you can see I have a blank document on
the screen and there are two ways of
accessing the headers and footers you
can go to the insert tab which brings up
the insert toolbar and then select
header and footer and alternatively you
can just click in the document and if I
just double click at the very very top
it will automatically open the header
and then I can just say what I wish to
put in to the header and for an example
I'm going to insert the date and time so
if I select the date and time icon going
to select which format that I wanted to
display in and I'll select the second
one down so I select on there and that
will give me the date in the header the
beauty of using the headers and footers
is that when you make changes are you
move further down the page and the
document size increases so far scroll
down and just move on to another page as
you can see it's all a muddle the end of
the date on to that page similarly if I
wish to add pH numbers I would just
scroll to the bottom of the document and
again I can go to the insert tab or I
can just double click right at the very
bottom of the document which will open
the footer and then a canard pH number
so the select page number and then I
would obviously a select the alignment
so I do want Elaine to the right center
or left and I'm going to go for the
center select or care and that will
insert a page number into the footer and
as you can see that is carried through
on every page
you can't access the head doesn't foot
us at anytime so I can click away from
that and then work on my document
perhaps I wanted to make a change to the
deed format so I could just double click
back into that highlight the deed form
up and select a different way of
displaying it select or care and that
will change that and again if I wanted
to change how the footer or the page
number in the footer is displayed
I could double click in the footer
highlight the number and select page
number maybe that I want to right align
that select your care and then will
automatically right align it you can't
also insert images on other information
into the header as required